William Kurniawan

https://williamk19.com/

Email: williamkurniawan1144@gmail.com Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/williamk19 Github: github.com/williamk19

SUMMARY

Fresh graduated software engineering student from Institut Teknologi Telkom Surabaya. Having a good knowledge about Web Development. Currently study about Frontend Engineering with React.js and Next.js, and Backend Development using Laravel. Have some experience working in a team with software development methodologies like Agile Scrum and Kanban Style. Want to learned more about other frontend technologies in the future and collaborating on open source projects.

EXPERIENCE

PasarPolis South Jakarta, Remote

Software Engineer Intern (Frontend)

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- $\circ~$ Develop and manage reusable components throughout the frontend web application.
- o Learn Next.js and other libraries to support web application development and performance.
- Work on several bug fixes to improve user experience.

JavaScript / React.js / Next.js

IT Telkom Surabaya

Surabaya, On Site

Reasearch Assistant

Jun 2021 - Oct 2022

- \circ Develop management system for students internship at IT Telkom Surabaya using codeigniter 4 framework.
- Develop and implement AI software to maintain physical distancing among Dalegan Beach visitors using Python, Yolo, NVIDIA Jetson Nano.

PHP / Codeigniter / Python / MariaDB

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Telkom Surabaya

Surabaya, Indonesia

Bachelor of Computer in Software Engineering (S.Kom.); GPA: 3.98

Sep. 2019 - Mar. 2023

- Frontend Mentor of Web Dev Workshop (WAOW S3) by Coder IT Telkom Surabaya.
- o Coordinator of competitive programming division for CODER IT Telkom Surabaya.
- Participate in internal activites (LKTI, Sport Competition, and Competition Organizer).

PROJECTS

• TRVLX

https://app.skytravelink.my.id

Implemented Travel Booking System using Laravel and React (Inertia). This application is also implemented with pick-up and drop-off point selection feature using Geographical Information System libraries. There was some additional feature for maps routing optimization using nearest neighbor algorithm and Midtrans payment gateway.

• SIMANIS

Information system for internship management for Institut Teknologi Telkom Surabaya. Made with Codeigniter 4 framework, PHP, Bootstrap UI Library, Myth, and other tools. This software is developed with Agile Scrum methodologies.

SKILLS

- Languages: Indonesia (Native), English (Intermediate)
- Technologies: JavaScript (React.js, Next.js, Node), PHP (Laravel Codeigniter), React Native, Java, Python